Nathaniel Bowman

A self-directed and motivated audio engineer/programmer who reads the documentation and studies sound more than one should. Strong skills in web app & cloud-based solutions. Proven expert in audio technologies and practices. Loves collaboration, problem-solving, and administrative organization/leadership who looks for creative solutions and propositions whenever possible. Currently embracing multiple projects and roles within the audio industry with industry-leading brands!

EXPERIENCE

LightFeather.IO LLC, Remote — Full Stack & DevOps Engineer OCTOBER 2021 - PRESENT

Modernizing disparate legacy transactional applications into forward-leaning, AWS cloud-native applications. Develop front end services for web applications using industry-standard technologies including React, Angular, and TypeScript. Develop backend services for web applications using industry-standard technologies including Express.js, Spring Boot, and ASP.NET in tandem with building RESTful API services. Manage pipeline provisioning and deployments from development to production using tools including Jenkins, Terraform, GitHub Actions, SonarQube, and AWS Amplify and AWS CloudFormation. Assisting with business and technical discovery to help customers meet their objectives and minimize technical debt. Performing in accordance with pre-designed interface standards, quality assurance standards, performance standards, and cost-benefit analysis of modern, forward leaning applications and information systems in the cloud. Assist DevOps teams with tests and staging tasks using tools including Jenkins, Terraform, Sonarqube, Docker, and Ansible. Providing modern architecture using common data stores, system security, API managed services, Identity Access Management (IAM), reporting and visualization Tools; and hosting and infrastructure requirements.

Freelance Audio Engineering, Remote — Audio Engineering & Development

JANUARY 2017 - PRESENT

A multi-faceted role with tasks falling into both audio and computer engineering. Ensuring high-quality recording, producing, sound-design, mixing & mastering, and often times assisting with composition and writing of source material. Assisting with equipment setup/teardown for live productions. Performing consultations and development for digital audio products using tools & technologies including JUCE, Projucer, C/C++, Python, React, and other miscellaneous technologies. Managing publication, artist relations, marketing and branding, communications, and label management for specific clients. Check out who's used my work in the Industry Affiliations section.

Best Buy, Lacey, WA — Technical Sales Advisor

JUNE 2021 - OCTOBER 2021

Handle all aspects of sales including: customer contracts and warranties, customer payments, cash and credit card/check transactions. Develop, maintain and communicate strong, up-to-date knowledge of wireless products, accessories, pricing plans and service features. Advise customers of solutions based on the products and deals provided by the company. Provide input on products and their capacities to assist customers with their own solutions.

Van Law Firm, Tacoma, WA — Contracted IT Technician

MARCH 2021 - JULY 2021

Ensured quality and longevity of telecommunications systems and in-house computers. Handling system errors "on-call" and resolving technical problems efficiently when they happen. Advised CEO of system requirements and



317 N Ave. 50, Apt 02 Los Angeles, CA 90042 (626) 428-5636

nathanielrbowman@gmail.com dev.actuallyitsnathaniel.com github.com/actuallyitsnathaniel Linkedin: in/actuallyitsnathaniel

SKILLS

Audio Recording/Engineering, Composition, Mixing & Mastering, Sound Design, Audio Repair, Hardware Repair, Agile Methodologies, SCRUM, Software Planning & Development, Network Administration, Team **Collaboration**, Planning & Organization, Collaboration, Critical Thinking, Communications, Leadership, Database Administration & Management

CERTIFICATIONS

SoloLearn, Java Certification ID#: 1068-13051709

Audinate, Dante Level 2 AVIXA Certification Committee

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES

Ableton Live 9-11, Logic Pro X, Pro Tools, FL Studio 9-20, JUCE/Projucer, Sibelius, Izotope RX, Adobe CC, VS Code, Java, Javascript, Typescript, C/C++, C#, Python, Git, GitHub, Jenkins, AWS, Terraform, PHP, CSS, HTML5, Spring (MVC), Node.js, React, React Native, ASP.NET, .NET (Core), G Suite, Google Apps Scripts, Google Cloud Platform, MS Office Suite

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Music Industry - 5+ yrs Live Production - 4+ yrs Software Engineering - 3+yrs upgrades as needed. Debugged software implementations when applicable using technologies including Google Apps Script.

Azusa Pacific University (APU), Azusa, CA — IT Support Tech

DECEMBER 2020 - MAY 2021

Worked with customers to troubleshoot computer systems in addition to software/hardware installation and licensing. Maintained quick response times in emails regarding troubleshooting and forwarding information.

APU, Azusa, CA — Live-Production Systems Engineer

DECEMBER 2018 - MAR 2020

Maintained computer systems and networks, along with hardware integrity. Worked closely with clients, internal staff and other stakeholders to determine planning, implementation and integration of system-oriented projects for better *data management and organization*. Debugged software implementations when applicable. Utilized Google Apps Scripts.

EDUCATION

Azusa Pacific University, Azusa, CA — *Double Major*, B.S. Computer Information Systems and Honors Humanities

August 2016 - May 2021

PROJECTS

Untitled Eva Beat Project — *An AI Tool for Content Creators*

May 2022 - PRESENT

A new conceptualization of Eva Beat's "Melody Sauce", planned to be a generative audio content tool with implementations of AI/ML for integration with social media platforms. Roles and contributions are currently in discussion.

Sam Denton — Recording Artist & Brand

JULY 2019 - PRESENT

An artist project I currently produce, compose, write, mix and master for. Together we handle songwriting, publishing, branding, and marketing campaigns. Currently building a catalogue for future contract deals and investments. Handling a breadth of communications that consist of playlisting, curator placement, social exposure and other pursuits in branding.

Ryland — Keys, Vocals, Co-Production for Band

AUGUST 2019 - PRESENT

Performing sold-out shows with keys, synths, sampling, and vocals for the band. Assist with co-production on select works. Building a catalogue for future contract deals and investments. Responsible for a breadth of communications that include playlisting, curator placement, social exposure and other pursuits in branding.

Melody Sauce 2 Presets — Set of Presets for New AI-Driven VST

JANUARY 2021 - MARCH 2021

Evabeat's Melody Sauce plugin is designed to output melodies in the key and 'emotion' that the producer designates. Developed synth presets in a separate plugin synthesizer. Converted sounds to soundfont (.sfz) format using Python scripts, and ran them through a rudimentary python program for fx and other parameters to be later implemented with the VST.

Aubit Sound — Sound Design and Audio Engineering

JANUARY 2019 - DECEMBER 2020

Produced presets for multiple plugins such as NI's Massive and Xfer's Serum.

INDUSTRY AFFILIATIONS:

Lauv, U2, Martin Garrix, Cinesamples, Virginia to Vegas, Sam Denton, Brodyn, John White, KRPTK, Ryland, Eva Beat, Aubit Sound, John Lowell Anderson, Matthew & Melanie Tryggestad Created Ableton Project Sessions. Recorded and produced loops and samples for numerous library packs. Created video tutorial content for sample libraries and general audio tutorship. All sounds were placed in a set and emphasized the sound of pre-existing artists for marketability. As of 2019, Aubit Sound's confirmed customers include LAUV, Cheat Codes, Virginia to Vegas, and U2.

Fiber Path Generation — *Database Parsing Function for G Suite*

A Google Apps Script that creates a custom menu for Google Sheets. It iterates through cells with corresponding values which generate a string that reveals the interconnected route between them, which is incredibly useful for revealing paths of documented (but poorly organized) fiber optic cabling between the two main campuses of Azusa Pacific University. Its function has served the Live Production Dept. very well and I believe they continue to use it.

CUBE Mobile App — Software Engineering Senior Capstone

AUG 2020-MAY 2021

Full-stack, agile development with a team of 5 to build a polymorphic mobile app that expedites space research while also minimizing its cost by accessing and relaying parsed telemetry of a CubeSat to one's smartphone, utilizing the computing power and security of Google Cloud Platform. Built with React Native. Check my github for the repo!

A Merrier World: Unsung Virtues of Middle-earth — Honors Humanities Senior Capstone

AUG 2019-MAY 2020

Foreword by *Sean Aston. A.k.a. Samwise Gamgee.* A published work that delves into the nuances of Tolkien's writings to reveal poignant, yet, overlooked truths. Worked cross-functionally with a team of people to write and publish this book. My primary contribution to this work is its chapter on Courage.

ISBN: 9781735278810